Finding Aid for the Recordings of June in Buffalo, 1975-1978, 1980
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Concert recordings, 1975-1978, 1980, I; Reel 1-2, 7-68
  - June in Buffalo Concert 49: Music of Ralph Shapey, June 10, 1980, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 69-70. Preservation master on DVD 52. (Box 2, Reel 62)
    Evocations (1959)
    Performers: Douglas Cone, violin; Jan Williams, percussion; Aki Takahashi, piano
    Work number: JIB49_004
    Quartet, strings, no. 7 (1972)
    Performers: Kronos Quartet: David Harrington, John Sherba, violins; Hank Dutt, viola; Joan Jeanrenand, violoncello
    Duration: 35:21
  - June in Buffalo Concert 50: String quartets of Lejaren Hiller, June 11, 1980, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 71-72. Preservation master on DVD 53. (Box 2, Reel 63)
    Work number: JIB50_001
    Quartet, strings, no. 6 (1972)
    Duration: 27:05
    Work number: JIB50_002
    Quartet, strings, no. 7 (1979)
    Duration: 30:56
    Work number: JIB50_003
    Quartet, strings, no. 3 (1953)
    Duration: 29:16
  - June in Buffalo Concert 51: Music of George Crumb, June 12, 1980, 2 10-inch reels of audio tape; Transferred to CD 73-74. Preservation master on DVD 54-55. (Box 2, Reel 64-65)
    Work number: JIB51_001
    Makrokosmos (Volume I, 1972)
    Performers: Aki Takahashi, amplified piano
    Duration: 34:41
    Work number: JIB51_002
    Makrokosmos (Volume II, 1973)
    Duration: 35:34
    Work number: JIB51_003
    Performers: Yvar Mikhashoff, Aki Takahashi, pianos; Jan Williams, Bruce Penner, percussion
    Duration: 38:50
    Work number: JIB51_004
    Celestial mechanics (Makrokosmos IV, 1979), four hands
    Duration: 25:20
  - June in Buffalo Concert 52: Music of Christian Wolff, June 13, 1980, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 75-76. Preservation master on DVD 56. (Box 2, Reel 66)
    Introductory remarks by Christian Wolff (5:47).
    Work number: JIB52_001
    Exercises 15-16 (1975)
    Performers: Christian Wolff, piano
    Duration: 12:13
    Work number: JIB52_002
    Exercises 17 (1975)
    Duration: 8:18
    Work number: JIB52_003
    Hay una mujer desaparecida (1979) after Holly Near
    Duration: 15:30
    Introductory remarks by Christian Wolff (3:28).
    Work number: JIB52_004
    Braverman music (1978)
    Performers: Bunita Marcus, bass clarinet; Jan Williams, percussion; Robert Dick, flute; James Kasprowicz, trombone; Christian Wolff, piano
    Duration: 28:45
  - June in Buffalo Concert 53: "Stimmung", by Karlheinz Stockhausen, June 14, 1980, 2 10-inch reels of audio tape; Transferred to CD 77-79. Preservation master on DVD 57-58. (Box 2, Reel 67-68)
    Music fragment and introductory remarks, possibly by Heinz Rehfuss (13:29).
    Work number: JIB53_001
    Stockhausen, Karlheinz, 1928-2007
    Stimmung (1968)
    Performers: Jocelyn Alaimo, Jay Anstee, John Kasprowicz, Christine Marstrand, Carol Ann Sirmay, voices; Heinz Rehfuss, Paul Gallagher, conductors
    Duration: 2:09:31 (divided over 3 CDs)
- John Cage lectures, June 4-June 6 1975, II; Reel 3-6
  The compact discs are arranged in order matching the numbering of the original reel to reel tapes, Reel 03-Reel 06.
  The spines of the original containers of the reel to reel tapes are dated June 3, June 4, and June 5; the spine of the fourth reel is missing. The reformatted CDs were all incorrectly dated June 3 1975. However, auditioning the recordings reveals dates as stated below. The June 5 and June 6 are dated with certainty; the June 4 dates are less certain. Jeff Simon wrote an article in the June 21 1975 Buffalo Evening News titled "Composer Cage: Stung by followers". It contains details, including specific quotations of remarks by Cage, about lectures presented by Cage on June 2, June 3, and June 5. None of the details from the June 2 and June 3 lectures can be matched to content on the recordings below.
  - John Cage lectures at June in Buffalo, June 4 1975 and June 5 1975, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 80-81. Preservation master on CD Box 3 CD 1-2. (Box 3, Reel 3)
    CD 80, Track 1 (11:00): June 4 1975 (Wednesday). First spoken line: "…such an exchange of ideas … among those exchanges Christian [Wolff] brought to me the I ching which had been published by his father."
    CD 80, Track 2 (24:44): June 5 1975 (Thursday). This is the first part of the lecture in which Cage responds to the S.E.M. performance of Song Books on Wednesday June 4.
    CD 81, Track 1 (10:20): June 5 1975 (Thursday). This is the second part of the lecture in which Cage responds to the S.E.M. performance of Song Books on Wednesday June 4.
    CD 81, Track 2 (24:43): June 5 1975 (Thursday). This is the third part of the lecture in which Cage responds to the S.E.M. performance of Song Books on Wednesday June 4.
    Online access to the recording of the lecture and an annotated transcription has generously been made available courtesy of the John Cage Trust.
  - John Cage lecture at June in Buffalo, June 4 1975, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 82-83. Preservation master on CD Box 3 CD 3-4. (Box 3, Reel 4)
    CD 82, Track 1 (61:41): June 4 1975 (Wednesday). First spoken line: "This morning at the rehearsal, not all of you were there, we got involved in a discussion towards the end [about] the publication of music."
    CD 83, Track 1 (32:24): June 4 1975 (Wednesday). First spoken line: "But find out how to go on and I would warn against coming down to depending on your spontaneity."
  - John Cage lecture at June in Buffalo, June 6 1975, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 84-85. Preservation master on CD Box 3 CD 5-6. (Box 3, Reel 5)
    CD 84, Track 1 (55:10): June 6 1975 (Friday). Begins with Cage telling a story about Lois Long and Morton Feldman.
    CD 85, Track 1 (40:56): June 6 1975 (Friday). Begins with a continuation of a discussion of Georgia O'Keefe's paintings.
  - John Cage lecture at June in Buffalo, June 6 1975, 1 10-inch reel of audio tape; Transferred to CD 86. Preservation master on CD Box 3 CD 7. (Box 3, Reel 6)
    CD 86, Track 1 (31:31): June 6 1975 (Friday). Begins with Cage in the midst of reviewing a student composer's work.
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Contributors
Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987
Subjects
Music festivals--New York (State)--Buffalo; Music--20th century; Cage, John
Genres
Sound recordings; Lectures
Associated Material
Index of composers
The following is a listing of all composers represented by works in the collection with links to the specific works.
Amy, Gilbert JIB46_004
Babbitt, Milton, 1916- JIB25_003 JIB28_001 JIB28_002 JIB28_003 JIB28_004 JIB28_005
Bartók, Béla, 1881-1945 JIB25_004
Beach, H. H. A., Mrs., 1867-1944 JIB14_002 JIB23_004
Berg, Alban, 1885-1935 JIB26_005
Boulez, Pierre, 1925- JIB17_003 JIB17_004
Brant, Henry, 1913-2008 JIB35_001 JIB35_002 JIB35_003 JIB35_004 JIB35_005 JIB35_006
Brown, Earle, 1926-2002 JIB04_002 JIB05_001 JIB05_002 JIB05_003 JIB05_004 JIB05_005 JIB05_006 JIB06_001
Cadman, Charles Wakefield, 1881-1946 JIB14_004
Cage, John JIB01_001 JIB01_002 JIB01_003 JIB01_004 JIB02_001 JIB02_002 JIB03_001A JIB03_001B JIB03_001C JIB03_001D JIB03_001E JIB03_002 JIB04_004 JIB27_004 JIB27_005 JIB27_006 JIB39_005 JIB39_006 JIB39_007 JIB39_008 JIB39_009 JIB46_002
Cage, John and Harrison, Lou JIB39_004
Carter, Elliott, 1908- JIB33_001 JIB33_002 JIB33_003
Chadwick, George Whitefield, 1854-1931 JIB14_005
Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990 JIB22_001 JIB22_002 JIB22_003 JIB22_004 JIB22_005 JIB22_006 JIB22_007
Cowell, Henry, 1897-1965 JIB27_001 JIB27_002 JIB27_003
Crumb, George JIB12_004 JIB19_001 JIB19_002 JIB21_001 JIB21_002 JIB21_003 JIB21_004 JIB21_005 JIB51_001 JIB51_002 JIB51_003 JIB51_004
Dessau, Paul, 1894-1979 JIB48_001
Dittrich, Paul Heinz JIB48_004
Druckman, Jacob, 1928-1996 JIB25_001 JIB32_001 JIB32_002
Edwards, Gus, 1879-1945 JIB14_010 JIB14_012
Farwell, Arthur George, 1872-1952 JIB23_001
Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987 JIB04_003 JIB06_002 JIB12_002 JIB13_001 JIB13_002 JIB42_001
Foss, Lukas, 1922-2009 JIB29_001 JIB29_002
Globokar, Vinko, 1934- JIB11_002
Gottschalk, Louis Moreau, 1829-1869 JIB14_006
Griffes, Charles Tomlinson, 1884-1920 JIB23_003
Harris, Chas. (Charles Kassell), 1867-1930 JIB14_015
Harrison, Lou, 1917-2003 JIB27_007 JIB27_008 JIB39_001 JIB39_002 JIB39_003
Herbert, Victor, 1859-1924 JIB14_014
Hiller, Lejaren, 1924-1994 JIB06_003 JIB06_004 JIB12_003 JIB16_001 JIB16_002 JIB16_003 JIB16_004 JIB16_005 JIB31_001 JIB31_002 JIB50_001 JIB50_002 JIB50_003
Ichiyanagi, Toshi, 1933- JIB44_004
Ives, Charles, 1874-1954 JIB15_001 JIB15_002 JIB15_003 JIB15_004 JIB15_005
Johnston, Ben JIB37_001
Jolas, Betsy JIB46_003
Kagel, Mauricio JIB11_004
Kai, Sesshu JIB44_001
Kondo, Jo, 1947- JIB44_002
Loeffler, Charles Martin, 1861-1935 JIB23_002
Loomis, Harvey Worthington, 1865-1930 JIB14_011
MacDowell, Edward, 1860-1908 JIB14_001 JIB14_003
Nemiroff, Isaac JIB30_001
Reich, Steve, 1936- JIB18_001 JIB18_002 JIB18_003 JIB18_004 JIB43_001 JIB43_003 JIB43_004
Riley, Terry, 1935- JIB24_001 JIB24_002
Romberg, Sigmund, 1887-1951 JIB14_009
Rzewski, Frederic JIB36_002
Satie, Erik, 1866-1925 JIB20_001 JIB20_002 JIB20_003 JIB20_004
Satoh, Somei, 1947- JIB44_007
Schenker, Friedrich JIB48_003
Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951 JIB17_001 JIB26_001 JIB26_002 JIB26_004 JIB26_006 JIB26_008 JIB26_009 JIB45_001 JIB45_002 JIB45_003 JIB45_004
Shapey, Ralph, 1921-2002 JIB49_001
Shapey, Ralph, 1921-2002 JIB49_002 JIB49_003 JIB49_004
Soegijo, Paul Gutama JIB11_001
Stockhausen, Karlheinz, 1928-2007 JIB53_001
Stromberg, John JIB14_013
Takahashi, Yuji, 1938- JIB44_006
Takemitsu, Toru JIB44_003
Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989 JIB40_001 JIB40_002
Vigeland, Nils JIB47_001 JIB47_002 JIB47_003
Voigtländer, Lothar, 1943- JIB48_002
Von Tilzer, Harry, 1872-1946 JIB14_008
Webern, Anton, 1883-1945 JIB17_002 JIB26_003 JIB26_007
Wolff, Christian, 1934- JIB04_001 JIB08_001 JIB09_001 JIB36_001 JIB52_001 JIB52_002 JIB52_003 JIB52_004
Wolpe, Stefan JIB25_002 JIB30_002 JIB30_003 JIB30_004 JIB30_005 JIB30_006
Won, Yong Sook JIB46_001
Work, Henry C. (Henry Clay), 1832-1884 JIB14_007
Wuorinen, Charles JIB36_003 JIB38_001 JIB38_002 JIB38_003 JIB38_004 JIB41_001 JIB41_002
Xenakis, Iannis, 1922-2001 JIB10_001 JIB10_002 JIB11_003 JIB12_001
Yuasa, Joji JIB44_005
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
North American New Music Festival Catalog, 1983-1993
An online catalog of the festival performances.
Evenings for New Music, 1964-1980
An online catalog of the concert performances.